Um,
stocks just continue to uh defy whatever
goes on. Um, I'm going to go through
that today. I'm going to remind you guys
about bubbles, parabas, and speed
crashes and kind of give you some
insight into uh what we've seen the last
four to six weeks with inside AI. And
I'm going to say now that uh the
midcycle slowdown is ending. And it's
not that we're not going to see the rate
of change, but now this is no longer a
surprise. Uh positioning has shifted and
I'm starting to hear people that are
trying to be bearish start to come out
of the woodworks and highlight a whole
bunch of things which I'll go through.
Um it's been a sentiment and a technical
cleanse. Uh I'll go through why that is.
I'm going to go through the token index.
I I've been called more on this than
anything over the last three weeks both
from institutional from retail and from
very sophisticated tech people on why
this token index doesn't matter. Uh Meta
Apple interesting week uh I wrote a
paper on meta. I'm spending a lot of my
time on consumer AI agents which I think
is the next theme. I've talked about the
application side but I am going to start
to go through uh what is happening more
and more and what I think is going to be
a major story for the next 12 months.
Uh, I'm going to remind people about
exponential demand versus linear supply.
Scott Bessant did a speech and I spent a
lot of time on it this week with regards
to crypto. I'm going to basically start
to give you guys what I've talked about
now for the last month, which is
beginning a new um part of AI macro
Nexus, remind you what this was all for,
but combine it with what Scott Besson
said, what Mark Andre said regarding
Bitcoin, and this will be a new in the
same format as this, but very crypto
forward.
And we'll do a recap on what happened
with crypto this week. First of all, um
just in in general, uh I've had a lot of
success with RAAS. For those of you who
are financial advisors who want to spend
time uh on how the work that I'm doing
can be expanded more than just this
YouTube video and more than just a
subscriber site, uh I'll show you where
you can reach out. But uh between that
and especially the agency side of people
working on knowledge brains uh it's been
a uh a really good three weeks of
helping people not only stay on signal
with AI but also start to uh use it more
and more and I think that's helping. So
I just want to remind people what the
name was because this video this week
gets into why it's AI macro nexus. Uh AI
is no longer just a technology story.
It's becoming the dominant macro force
of the cycle. It changes productivity,
labor, inflation, capital spending,
energy, demand, digital assets, monetary
policy, market structure. The nexus is
the intersection of these forces, and
it's the place where investors connect.
The reason I bring this up, um,
everything that you're dealing with when
you're reading something on
productivity, on labor, on inflation, on
the Fed, on anything, AI is a part of
every single decision that's being made.
And that's why you have to be on top of
this. It's changing the world in front
of our eyes. Here's one example of it.
So, this is uh something I've shown a
bunch of times. I did a subscriber uh
video update where I started to go
through the fact that I think the
slowdown is reached a point where we've
done enough damage. Um, and this is
where the damage has been. This is the
60-day realized V of the technology
macro uh technology momentum factor from
Morgan Stanley. The white line here is
that. So, we've gone up and I've shown
this for a while. I showed it when it
was around 70. We're at 87 now. This is
through today on Friday. I'm doing this
Friday night. This is overlaid with the
S&P 60-day realize V. So, historically,
there's a correlation that does exist.
Meaning, if you're seeing tech momentum
V explode like this, you're usually
seeing the S&P V follow it. Now, the one
thing is tech has been going higher for
a while. This is why what we're doing is
this bubbles, parabas, and speed
crashes. This is what's going on. That's
why you have to be on top of this
because this is a structural bull
market. It is based on token demand.
Everything that I built everything on is
on token demand. This entire video by
the end should give you complete comfort
that we're not in a bubble that the
compute there is no excess capacity
because Meta is selling some off.
Hopefully you guys get there and you
realize that if that's true over the
next six months you're getting an
opportunity where this has gone higher.
has flushed people out across the globe
on retail, on hedge funds, everywhere
that people were using leverage and
probably overexposed. We've seen that
now come out mainly because the V's been
too high for people not to do it. S&P, I
don't know how you can look at that
chart and not be bullish. Um, I told
last week I showed it as a triangle.
You know, we get bad news out of Iran,
it still goes higher. We whatever you
want. We get sell off on Samsung on good
numbers. It still goes higher. This
triangle in the NDX is underperformed.
Again, tech is is lagging. We're getting
more exposure on financials, more
movement in healthcare. Uh but we did
finally start to see some tech bounce.
But again, this is a bullish looking
chart.
Uh this is a reminder if you guys didn't
see it, I did this video back on May
10th. Uh and the focus of this, which
was right around the first leg lower, is
about the way we should expect this to
trade. uh when you have bubbles and
parabas on the way up, you're going to
have speed crashes on the way down. If
this is all with inside a structural
bull market, which I'm going to continue
to say, this is a structural bull
market. You want to go with the river of
a macro bull market, especially when
you're in the first inning where you're
in the first inning of AI token demand.
Regardless of what anyone says that it
can't be the first inning based on the
charts, these charts were about people
being wrong on AI for two years saying
it was a bubble. It hallucinates. It's
not going to do anything. They had to
play catch-up once the earnings came in.
Then we hit the second derivative and
it's not going to be as easy from here.
So, it's not that this trade is going to
do what it did before. We are way past
the first inning of the speed of change.
But do I think that you're going to get
another five bagger in Micron and in SK
Heinex in these things over the course
of the next five years? It's very likely
you will, but that's less than the 20
bagger that occurred from March of last
year till now. So, we're going to slow
down because now everyone is aware of
it. So, Samsung uh released premill
preliminary quarterly profit up 19fold.
Micron fell that day. Samsung was down
that day.
Here's the chart and this is the first
thing I want to show. I saw three
separate YouTubes this week on the
market where they said this was a news
failure. See, good news came out. It
beat wound estimates and it sold off.
The problem is we had already sold off.
I don't subscribe to the fact that when
you've already had a correction, you've
already had weakening where we're
unchanged over the course of this when
you get good news that you should sit
there and say that this is bearish. Is
it something that showed that the
unwinds and the deleveraging were still
on? Yeah. But if you ask me what the
range is going to be and where the
support's going to be in this going
forward, I will tell you that I believe
this high from February, this low from
here, and this is going to be around the
bottom end of the range. And I think
we're going to be significantly higher
before the end of the year because of
what I'm going to show you.
This is the problem is that everyone is
looking for a correction. So if I told
you that over the 10 days in the two
days after that, this was the rolling
10day rate of change in Samsung. Okay,
it was the largest since the middle of
the COVID panic when we shut down the
world was 25 26%. This was 21. The only
other time that it was this big on a
10-day basis was just after Lehman
Brothers. So this is a speed crash. It
didn't feel like it. You don't think it
looks like it, but within a bull market,
this is a big fall, particularly when
you had these types of upsides that were
much bigger. So, these are the rolling
rate of 10day change. You had one at 35.
So, this has been a correction with
inside a bull market. Now, here's where
we are on a PE basis for next year. So,
everyone who wants to fade this, I
completely agree. If you believe in the
cyclicality of memory, you should
absolutely sit there and not pay
attention to this. If you believe that
the demand is going to stay at a very
high level and prices are going to stay
at a high level for the next three
years, this is way too cheap and argues
for a much higher PE than is normally
there. If you guys look at this and pay
attention, my PEG ratio, when we're
looking at the earnings growth relative
to the PE, they've already discounted
that this is going to slow down at these
levels. They've already built in a
bearish outcome in terms of multiples.
Here are how ridiculous the numbers are.
And this is why when people say this is
just like every other time, Samsung's
operating profit in 2026 could be over
$217 billion.
That's where analysts believe. Okay.
The company could generate more
operating profit this year than its
cumulative operating profit over the
past 40 years.
Don't treat this as a one-off event
where AI is just doing this and
everyone's over buying and then we're
going to run into a problem. It's silly.
Um, we're not even in the first inning
of token demand. I'm going to keep
saying it because nobody believed in
token demand until we got into January
of this year. And I will highlight in
some podcasts from Dylan Patel from Semi
analysis how much his spend has changed
and where he was in December of last
year to today. That should give you guys
a sense as to someone who's very
sophisticated on a growing business who
understands how to use AI and his team
does and how he went from $100,000
budget to $11 million over the course of
six months in terms of what his
annualized revenue spend is going to be.
So Korea's Cosby valuation falls to the
lowest since the global financial
crisis. Those are the types of things
you see at tops.
Joking. Um, here's Salesforce.com.
Everyone who is basically bearish on
memory are the same people who wanted to
buy Salesforce while it was coming down.
So Salesforce is now down to a 10p to
2028, 11 PE to next year. So again,
we've got a 4 PE on Samsung with their
earnings growing this year 524%
and for next year it's 43. They haven't
come close to meeting the estimates yet.
They've been above it by significant
numbers. And yet somehow or another,
this stock is trading at an 11p.
This is a problem. This is why from the
beginning of the year, I said you want
to be short abundance. Anything built on
code that can be replicated by a
computer. And you want to be long
scarcity. Anything that the spenders
are spending on that is physically
constrained by linear humans. That's it.
Humans build this, computers built this.
That theme will continue to permeate
because that's about the exponential
demand. So again, I put this in on June
8th. I started talking about the fact
that I was getting out of Micron in the
middle of May. Again, I got out way
before the top, but that was not my goal
to pick the top. My goal was to be in a
position where I'm probably going to be
buying some back at some point soon,
especially after the SKH Heinix deal
that went through today, just because
I'm hearing people be bearish. And I do
believe that 6 months from now, we will
be significantly higher than we are now.
Now that we've had some sort of
pullback, but also since we got another
earnings report and I'm no longer
worried about some of the things that I
thought could be an issue in terms of
the bottlenecks, it looks like we're
just going to be in a situation where
things are going to go at a slow pace.
Mainly because there are constraints
that are built in from humans that are
keeping this from being a bubble.
Believe it or not, it's the supply side,
the TSMC's that won't overbuild, the
fact that the gas turbines and all this
make it very difficult. We're finding
solutions to every problem on the power
side and they're finding ways to get
this done. So I just think that that's
going to keep prices at a higher level
because we're not going to be able to
get capacity on time. Uh the econ so the
navigating the AI midsight cycle
slowdown. I still believe with the
second derivative change but now that is
consensus in my opinion.
Here's what we did and this is part of
it. So you look not only for what I hear
from people but you want to see how much
damage we did. This is what happened.
We've given back now 50 or almost 50% of
the techo rally from Opus 4.5. And the
reason I care about Opus 4.5 is this is
when the change happened. This is when
people started to acknowledge it. This
is when people started to invest. And I
want you to look at this because it does
look a lot as I go through this from
February down then up looks a lot like
the token index as I get back to later.
And I'm not worried about the token
index, but I think the token index, uh,
people have started to use it for
something it shouldn't be used for. I
think that should go to zero over time.
Um, and more importantly, I don't think
it should be rising. I never think it
should be rising, and it technically
isn't, which I'll go through as well.
When these stories come out, it's
usually a good sign. Systematic long
short managers dropped 2.1% last week
through Thursday after declining 3.1%
over a 5day stretch. That was their
worst since December 23. On most of the
numbers that I've seen, they've given
back. And these are again systematic
long short managers. So these are quant
managers. They've given back about a
third of their year. They're still up
for the year. This is not some major
panic. I talked about this feeling a
little bit uh on the webinar that I did
this week for the subscribers about this
feeling a little bit like 2007. Um and
that it would end at some point around
the same time it did there, which was in
the first 10 days. I still think there
might be a little bit left, but I also
think the mutual funds have proven their
case of being underneath, which I
thought as well as they took down a lot
of this SKH Heinik deal. Um, fundamental
managers also fell and we know that the
pods had to close down as I talked about
because of how high the V was. Here's
the deleveraging on the retail side.
Even though we only had about a 23%
correction on the uh SKH Highix and
Samsung side down to about a 30 uh 38
and again this is back to Opus. The
retail side using the two times levered
gave back 62%.
So I think retail's been flushed. Morgan
Stanley put this out on their AI
beneficiaries and you can see the
massive outflow that occurred and we've
had three weeks of fairly large uh
outflows in terms of the net flows. Jeff
Degraphth, I like to combine this stuff.
This was a great one. Nearly 87% of S&P
500 semiconductor issues registered and
oversold on a 14-day basis. He uses
these lines. You can see these have all
been very good bottoms except for this
one here. all the others uh except for
these two little things here. So, could
it go lower? Of course, it could. But at
least you're getting also that on that
side. Here's what happened to my side in
terms of the technical sheet that I put
out. This was from May 29th, the week
ending. Look at these numbers. Percent
50day, 100, 91, 98. Look at the average
RSIs. Average RSIs. Everything was above
the 50 level. Here's where this week's
came in. Look how low these numbers are.
Percent above the 50-day. We've really
sold off here. You have one that's still
above, but the average RSIs
are now there and we still have
constructive none of the tech patterns
have changed. I'll go through that as
well. The score, they're good, meaning
this is a good entry point. Um, I show
this uh again, I've shown how to do this
and I will finish this video for you
guys in terms of how to be able to do
this on your own using Claude Co-work by
just updating the files. But this was
20-day of my 100 name thematic
portfolio. 73 of the 100 names were
above the 20-day on May 8th. We got down
to 21 on Wednesday when I did the uh uh
sub subscriber webinar to basically an
update to kind of give people a sense as
to where we are. Uh I like to see the
bump at the end of the week. We went
from 21 to 31. This definitely seems
like an oversold level. I mentioned last
week that when we get or I mentioned
this week when we get below 40 I get
very interested on the uh percent above
the 50-day and most importantly above
the 200 day it's back to the same level
it was kind of ending on the 26th but
these levels 50-day rising still at 76
and the 200 day rising which is the
critical one which is the bull market
structural situation is still up at 86
of the 100 names. We saw massive inflow
in the SOXX
and SKHEX today uh offering more than
seven times overs subscribed. It also
traded up. Here are the facts from the
memory side over the course of the last
three months
uh just in terms of what's gone on.
Memory chip crunch to persist until
2030. This was back during his earnings
in March 16th. If you thought anything
would change, this is what he said
today. Okay, the memory chip shortages
that are rolling the computer that are
roing the computer car and device
markets will probably persistent beyond
2030. So, we went from until 2030 to
beyond. Customers are signing long-term
contracts. Hadn't seen that before, but
remember Micron Inc.'s long-term supply
agreement is worth $und00 billion. Says
it has no idea when the RAM crisis will
end. This was less than a month ago.
Actually, it was less than three weeks
ago. and Dylan Patel
memory capacity is only growing 20 to
30% a year for the next three years.
This is the human capacity side. Demand
is doubling. This is the exponential dam
demand. Memory prices are going to keep
soaring. This is from an interview which
I will highlight which came out today.
Remember, Elon Musk is building a
terrafab
because he says there will not be enough
memory or chips for his humanoids
and the demand that he sees by 2030. I'm
going to get into that as we go on. I'm
showing you these things because this is
the reality of where we are. So, I want
to make this clear because I had I've
had multiple people now and I think this
is because there's a bunch of people on
next that have said this is just like
fracking. this will blow up.
The only thing that's just like fracking
is the amount of people that are saying
it's just like fracking. So, here's a
normal cycle before
AI. And I say before AI because this is
a typical demand cycle for hardwardriven
demand. So, hardware driven demand
meaning physical stuff. So if the demand
is driven by physical output and the
memory is a physical output, it's really
hard to get demand significantly away
from capacity. If the demand is now
digital and it's tokens and it increases
purely based on the productivity of the
models, but we need more memory. The
capacity can't grow any faster. The only
way to fix this problem is with an
algorithmic efficiency side of which
that is such a long shot that at this
point to get it to be able to do it to
be able to get it out there for every
it's just a long shot. Is it a hail
Mary? Will it eventually happen? I'm
sure it will. I don't think this is
going to get up to meet there anytime
soon particularly when I go through what
else is coming. So you have to remember
this is the difference. This is the old
world. This is the new world. This is
exponential growth. This gets important
when you start going into consumer
agents, full self-driving and humanoids.
These are all bigger demand for tokens
than what we have now. Just like chat
was here. Chat, we didn't have a
problem. We only had a problem when we
got into this period here when it became
evident that we were starting to hit a
part of the growth curve that was out of
control. This is why when you compare it
to the oil market, it's ridiculous. we
had a parabolic or an exponential move
on the supply side. The demand side
didn't move. So again, for everyone who
wants to compare these two, for every
smart oil guy or smart person who keeps
telling me this is the same as this,
I've seen this before. You haven't seen
this before because the demand is not
coming from human beings. The demand is
coming from computers. It's coming from
AI agents. It has nothing to do with
humans. Humans move on a linear scale.
It's very important for people to start
to realize this. That is where the bull
market lies. That is why I do this
stuff. Now, my next webinar will be on
July 15th, next week. I will
specifically go through names with
inside the portfolio that I think have
hit the levels that make sense. I will
go through the concentrated basket, all
10 names, and give you guys the details
on it. This is what the concentrated
basket has done now. So, we've hit the
50-day moving average. We did this back
in March 2 and then we got the next
liftoff, we hit the RSI, you guys can go
back and look and when the RSI gets down
here, the riskreward has sh has changed.
So when here when I thought there was a
midcycle slowdown, we've basically gone
sideways during this period. Now we can
reset and go. I reduced my position in a
bunch of these things down significantly
with Micron being the biggest one. I
kept some things the same. I moved some
things into silver and Bitcoin which
haven't worked out as well. I will now
go back and look at some of these names
and pick out the ones with inside the
concentrated basket. So, this is the
whole point of kind of helping you guys
not just on one side but also the other.
If you guys follow me on X, I put this
out uh on the same day I did the
subscriber webinar. Nvidia peaked on May
14th, three weeks before the AI
infrastructure trade peaked. So again,
if I go backwards and go over here and
you look into the middle of May
and basically go through, that was when
we saw the peak in the rate of change
and when we started to slow down. Well,
Nvidia peaked beforehand and more than a
month before SMH and the memory names
peak. Today is set to close above the
20-day moving average for the first time
since June 2nd, holding the 200 day and
with a MACD buy signal at the lowest
valuation in a decade. That is one of
the 10 names. So in the consensus
basket, Nvidia is one of the names. So
again for the RAAS and for anyone who is
new to this, if you want to reach out,
that's where the website is where you
can go find it. You can always reach out
to Mark Whailing at22V. He will help you
on anything you need, particularly on
the RAIA side. This is where I want to
get into the token expenditure index
because as I showed you before, if you
go through the es and flows on the
earlier chart I showed with the
everything related to this, including
the AI themes, I highlighted back here
in the middle of May when Nvidia peaked,
that this would be a growing risk, not
because it was a negative, but because
the narrative would start to change and
that's what we've seen. The narrative
has shifted. So, let's go through this.
The first rise in the token index was
the coding agent capability shock. Then
we had openclaw.
So open claw led to more users
immediately using agents that happen to
be AI native or Chinese.
Open claw was a big gamecher but it was
a sophisticated level. So most of the
token usage went to a lot of open-
source stuff. Then the enterprises
finally realized that they were missing
out. So the FOMO kicked in and every
single place whether it's Anthropics,
ARR, everything started to see a step up
function maxing from there. Token maxing
became a word. Everyone was on the
exploratory spend side. Then they saw
the bill shock and the token index goes
down. Not because everyone's bailing out
partly because school ended. All of
these different things that I talked
about. It's when the usage starts to go
more towards people that are using open
source, which AI native companies don't
stop. College students stop. People on
Morgan Stanley, Goldman Sachs, places I
know well, 20% of the people are out on
vacation or working remotely or they
don't work on Fridays. Whatever the case
is, you're not going to have as many
people using stuff as what was here. And
the bill shock kicked in. The problem is
with this whole analysis and with
everything going through it, it doesn't
include the amount of adoption that's
still happening. We have massive
adoption happening. This is not an an
index of making or losing money as I
will show with the Dylan Patel side. So
again, memory shortage exponential token
usage going higher every single day.
I've heard people argue with me that
nobody's going to use the most expensive
stuff. That is a bunch of garbage.
If you want to go hear someone who talks
about this and I think always does a
good job in an interview, this came out
today. Dylan Patel or one on Thursday I
guess late uh Dylan Patel on wisdom tree
in Europe good interview I think the
highlights that I have here Patel argues
the AI ROA debate is missing how quickly
serious users are increasing token spent
and he highlights again that semi
analysis spend went from less than
100,000 now the reason it was 100,000 in
November which is a very similar story
to me he was paying for everyone at the
firm for a 200 $00 Claude model. Once
Claude Code started to be able to work
after Opus 4.5 and build stuff, that's
when they went to a token spend side and
everyone started to spend there. By
January, it was already $4 million
annualized.
It stands at a roughly 11 million
annualized today and the peak week was
equivalent to 14 million. That's for a
90 person firm.
Companies are blowing through AI
budgets, but the right response may be
cutting other SAS or legacy spend rather
than cutting AI. The right model choice
depends on the workload. Cheaper models
for fixed workflows, smartest models for
assistant work. This part and I h you
have to listen to this. For assistant
style work, the smartest model can be
cheaper overall because it uses fewer
tokens, fewer iterations, and less human
time. This is why when you look at the
labor market, we have weekly hours. If
you can get things done in onetenth the
time, but you're spending more money for
it, that's the way it should work. So
his point being, we are in the stage of
enterprises trying to figure out what to
do, how much they should be using for
workflows, which will be much cheaper,
and how much they should be using for
assistance style work. You don't hire
all people from the most expensive
colleges with the best resumes. A team
at a firm is broken up by a lot of
different areas. You hire younger people
which are cheaper than the domain
experience people. That is the way AI
will work. He goes through memory is no
longer a normal commodity cycle. If you
don't believe me, he goes through more
of the technical reasons. He expects
memory prices to keep rising until AI
gets enough supply and consumer devices
like smartphones and laptops are forced
to absorb higher prices. Basically
saying the same thing as the Samsung. We
have a shortage where the phones, the
cars, the PCs, we don't have enough
memory. So the demand is coming not just
from hyperscalers for data centers. It's
coming from everybody. He's bullish on
CPU. There's a CPU thing in there. I
think it's worth listening to as well.
Uh on the power side, he's been the best
by far in my opinion on what's been
happening. I've used him a lot. I've
referenced him a lot. This was another
great one. Basically what he said in a
summary with me listening to it and
going through it, we're figuring a way
to get the gigawatts done, even if it
means using diesel truck boat train
engines converted for power generation,
you have to listen to it to understand
that if you thought we were going to run
out of compute because people are going
to stop the data centers, it's not the
case. He went through and obviously I I
I'm pretty sure he's an investor, but if
he's not, he obviously has access.
You're getting more and more of this
that Anthropic is going cash flow
positive or at least reaching operating
profit.
Again,
this just means the margins are coming
through and the RAIC should not be there
uh in terms of a fear. But I did do this
on the AI capex air pocket. If you guys
didn't read it because of the vacation,
I would go read it. I I spent some time
I've spent a lot of time on consumer
agents, but I really spent time on this
Mark Zuckerberg town hall reportedly
acknowledging the Meta Zentic AI
progress had been slower than expected.
And I make the argument that if they did
end up selling any of their capex
capacity, it would be because they can't
get their consumer agents working the
way they want yet. It's coming, guys.
And if you want to go listen, this came
out one day ago. Meta or two days ago.
The CTO of Meta, Andrew Bosworth, was on
with Alex Canantrowitz. It's a great
interview and it's very simple to go
listen. The industry is moving beyond
one giant monolithic model. I think he
talks about the fact that there's going
to be open source and there's going to
be the frontier models. Consumer AI has
been slow because the products are still
too hard to use. This is a really
critical part especially for mutual
funds and longerterm investors to spend
time on understanding how consumer
agents are going to change the world
which is a dramatic shift. Whatever
happened with coding agents which is for
the language of agents this is massively
bigger. This is far bigger in importance
than opus 4.5. So think of it this way.
All we've done is increase the ability
to code but we haven't found the ability
to get through all of this yet. It is
incredibly
important to understand what that means.
Consumer AI has been slow because the
product layer is still immature, not
because the model's weak. For consumer
AI to work, it has to disappear into
daily life like search maps, messaging,
or the camera. I use my uh Grock in my
Tesla this week. I had a conversation
with it on the drive, the entire drive.
I cannot do that with a phone the same
way. It's not as good until we get to
the point that you are speaking to it
like you were supposed to with Alexa
where you can be sitting there cooking
and asking it questions on what the
recipe is. So you don't have to go to
your phone, you don't have to go look at
it. Until we get to that point, which is
coming soon, it's really hard to get the
habit formation. But once it happens,
billions of users will start having
agents working for them and they will
start giving them things to do, but they
need the context, the trust, the timing,
the permissions. It is extremely
complicated and the frontier models are
not capable of doing that. The token
curve changes because of all of these
things. Frequency goes up, context
length goes, multi-step reasoning
because of all of the things you need in
here. Every single thing will be on
there. Every single thing that is the
next function.
When the consumer AI interface problem
is solved, token usage should explode.
AI moves from being something people
occasionally summon to something that is
working in the background. So it goes
through before the iPhone mobile data
existed but usage was constrained by
friction. You have to go back and think
about what happened with bandwidth and
what's going to happen with consumer
agents. The problem is what happened
with bandwidth again and getting it
there was a very slowmoving thing. Once
we hit the phone and we're getting
closer and I'm going to show you not
just this is all the meta side but you
have to go look at what happened to
Apple stock because Apple's also a part
of this because of the phone. So once it
happens, these are going to start
consuming an enormous amount of tokens.
So coding agents were the first visible
token explosion
and that they would consume a thousand
more tokens. This is why once we hit the
coding side with Opus 4.5, everyone had
to adjust. Consumer agents
bigger user base lower initially.
Goldman has reportedly estimated that AI
agents could drive token consumption up
roughly 24 times
to around 120 quadrillion
per month.
FSD robo taxis not tokens in the API
sense but enormous video compute. Um
Elon Musk has talked about this to be
able to get to the point where this
works completely. have a lot a lot of
work to do and this is why I went
through a lot of things with the visual
l the VLMs uh in terms of the instead of
the LLMs humanoids again a combination
of the VLMs but the step function is
enormous in terms of what you're going
to need compute-wise if you haven't gone
through it yet you should
we have a lot more demand coming for
compute so again coding agents then we
get consumer agents this is why we're in
the first inning right now. This only
started the beginning of this year. And
you can go look at Dylan Patel's answer.
It's only been five months. We are in
the beginning stages of what it'll take
five years to get to here. If you just
do it on a time basis, we're barely in
the first inning. It's just going to
continue to go. The compute demand is
exponential because each wave changes
the unit of consumption. It grows
exponentially because every capability
threshold creates a new consumption
surface. This is why humans can't keep
up with this. We are used to seeing
linear change. We are thinking of memory
in a linear framework.
They wrote a positive piece on meta. Uh
I'm getting more interested in this
consumer agent thing and the upside
potential. And in particular, I just
want to bring up this. This is Apple
stock price as we got to all-time highs.
We actually closed at all-time highs
yesterday on a closing basis. That there
is when they did their AI Siri
announcement. It made an all-time high.
It sold off. That was a sell the news
event. That was something that to me
looked bearish except for the fact that
we're above the 200 day. So, we trade
down, not just one day, but two days. We
have a very weak bounce. Then we go down
and on this day, this is the day that
they announced they're raising prices
20% because of the memory prices. We
know there's going to be less handsets
sold. So, what happens? Goes right back
to all-time highs. When I start seeing
that kind of activity and I'm reading
about consumer agents coming and this
stock is expensive on a PEG ratio basis,
I'm starting to think there's a lot more
to this story than what is going on.
Now, if you don't buy into the stuff I
just said in terms of uh all of the
things about the future, you don't
believe in humanoids, you don't believe
in in consumer agents, you think it's
going to take years to get there, you
don't think Meta's doing any of the
things I said for these reasons, I'm
just getting sick of hearing that
there's too much capacity when
Microsoft, this is all in the most
recent earnings period, strong customer
demand continues to exceed capacity.
Google's allocating compute under a
robust ROIC framework, meaning they're
only allocating places where they can
get back revenue. Uh, Trrenium largely
sold out. Tranium 3 nearly fully
subscribed to much of tranium for
already reserved. Meta said it's compute
constrained and that it had
underestimated compute demand. Again,
this is from the last earnings. So, this
is not long ago. The backlog in terms of
orders that they have, commitment
quotes, 627 billion for Microsoft, 462
billion for Google, 225 billion for
Amazon, 638 billion for Oracle. The
demand is there guys, it's already
there. Uh if you don't believe that,
let's just look at the prices of the uh
the GPUs. As Dylan Patel talked about in
the interview, he said CPUs can run to a
price where they start to actually run
in GPUs. We just don't have enough. We
still have we we still are seeing the
need for them as we're building out data
centers and it's going to continue. So
rental rates, we're just not seeing it
there. Uh
this is the way o bullish oil curves are
supposed to to look. Um the rental curve
again. So this is from the semi analysis
guys just using the silicon data
according to our data compute market
continues to tighten.
Um in terms of the capex buildout and
the latest forecast semi analysis is at
11.1 trillion well above Goldman's 7.6
trillion
and pretty much everyone else has no
figures that extend that thus far. Here
are their numbers. So again, you get
this big step function. It's g the
second derivative kicks in. We're not
going to get a doubling. We're going to
get a slow every year is going to be
slower growth, but the numbers are
enormous. The spend is enormous, and
it's just going to take all this time.
JP Morgan put something out this week.
Again, multiple ways to look at it. Uh
everything is bullish. So when you go
through stuff and you realize that all
of this stuff is bullish and we're in a
race around the globe, it's just not
slowing down, guys. Um, in terms of the
token usage, uh, I think this was a good
article. So Aaron Levy put this out.
Great post on how to think about open
source AI and applied AI layer. Two
things will always be true in AI.
Frontier intelligence will likely remain
at the forefront. Again, think about
what Dylan Patel said of solving brand
new use cases and often be used for
orchestrating and planning in any type
of complex workflow. I don't know how
this is a a a shock to people. The the
the best intelligence will always be
used by enterprises for at least some of
what's going on.
And in many cases, it's going to be
cheaper. And that's where the margin is.
At the same time, as use cases become
mature and predictable and become
workflows, yeah, you'll use lower or
close models. Yeah, I'm already doing
that. So are most people. This is not
something new. If you want to go read
the story, this is from uh Jesse Zang.
And again, we run 90% of our workloads
on open-source models instead of open AI
or anthropic. This is consistent with
most of the hyperrowth app companies.
Enterprises won't get to this number for
a while. They're still going to have the
best models. They're still going to be
trying to focus on this stuff. But
eventually, as they get more
sophisticated to get there, enterprises
spend as a whole is moving the opposite
direction as AI native firms. Open
source models just fell to 11% of
enterprise spend down from 19%. The
piece argues that the popular native
open source is eating enterprise is
directionally right over the long term,
but wrong in the current spending data.
Closed models dominate early stage
discovery. Open source wins the later
stage production.
more in token budgeting. Same type of
thing from uh from semi analysis, Dylan
Patel's group. And again, you can just
see that everyone is spending more on
AI. It's not changing. We're not seeing
some fall. Now, Palanteer is talking
their book, but I think this is worth
the read. Uh they put this out this
week. He's been all over trying to argue
that you want to own your own stuff
before anthropic and open AI steal it.
Uh obviously, he's talking his own book.
It's still a name in my 100 name
portfolio. I still own it myself, too.
Um, it's been a long time. I It's I
bought it around 130. It's still around
130. Uh, and I bought it back in I think
the first quarter earnings report, which
was Februaryish, I believe, uh, early
February when I was on on trip. So, it's
been consolidating and it looks like a
consolidation, but I happen to agree
that a lot of places are going to take
Palunteer seriously and actually do what
they're saying. So, worth going through.
Um, I'm not going to read all this
because you guys can go through it, but
I do think there's a lot of good points
in here that are in that are important.
5.6 came out this week. Uh, barely have
used it so far. Very impressed. A lot of
the feedback's been great. I'll spend
time on it. Uh, this story has me
interested. I haven't spent enough time
on it. Uh but
basically we're starting to get to the
point with AI where the conscious
side is coming up. Uh I think it's very
interesting. If there's anything useful
there, I will bring it, but I haven't
spent enough time. I've listened to the
Moonshots episode from this week, which
there was nothing in it for me to bring
to you guys. Uh and they talked about it
and I have had some I've watched some
videos and stuff, but nothing big. Uh
I'm getting back here because
this is the beginning of something that
for all of you is a must. Uh very seldom
do I say that. I know most of the people
listening uh have views on Bitcoin. They
have views on crypto. They're not the
same. The traditional finance people,
I'm sure, are more on the negative side
and the crypto people that watch this
video are more on the positive side.
Well, here's the deal. You're past the
point now of ignoring it. And the AO
macacro nexus was two things. It was the
disruption that would come from AI on
the traditional world. How it would
impact economics, government decisions,
how it would impact earnings, how it
impact the stocks. All of that has
happened. Every single one of the things
and the reason that I chose to do this
has happened. Once we got to consumer
agents, the next phase was that the
financial guardrails would change and it
would be one of the most important
things in the history of the world. We
have been on a banking system this way
for a long, long time. Swift has been
around for a long long time. This is all
ending. It's all changing. It's all
morphing. And there is money to be made
on this and lost. And that is what the
next phase and why I'm starting a new
YouTube channel specifically starting
from the crypto side spending at least
20 of the 30 minutes I expect to do this
on what's happening with inside crypto
so people can learn how to con speak in
crypto how to speak in tokenization how
to speak in stable coins how to speak in
the new payment system. So Matt Hogan,
who I enjoy very much, uh, and was on a
panel with him once before,
he posted this and it just got me going.
And this was on Wednesday. Did and this
is related to a Scott Bessett
speech that he did, I believe, at the uh
economic the New York economic club.
Within that speech, he said, "Digital
assets, stable coins, tokenization, new
payment system will help to shape the
future of money."
He referenced that El Muhammad Alerian
calls it a remarkably important speech.
I posted this today. I think everyone
whether you believe in crypto or not
needs to read both the Scott Bess
impeach and the Muhammad Alan New York
Times oped about the importance of the
speech for Wall Street. You can no
longer have no view on crypto. You
cannot just call it speculative and walk
away. This will disrupt businesses,
public stocks. we will have
tokenization. So the point is do your
homework now. If you don't believe me
and you've ignored all this, then go
read these articles. Go read the speech
from Scott Besson. Here's the uh the
op-ed from Muhammad Alan. Argues Scott
Besson has articulated a new a new US
economic doctrine. This administration
is in place for the next two and a half
years. His main point is that Wall
Street and economists have not fully
internalized how big this shift is.
Instead, the US now sees economic
security as inseparable from national
security. That means trade, investment,
technology, standards, supply chains,
tariff, exports, and payment systems and
the dollar's role are all becoming tools
of strategic power. The old
globalization framework is over.
This is really critical. The AI part,
they put the AI action plan. They have
focused on getting the clarity act
through. It's not through yet. The
genius uh act went through last year. on
digital asset payments. Best at Alian's
point is crypto is being reframed
from a speculative
sideshow into a tool of US financial
statecraft. The future of money will be
shaped by digital assets, stable coins,
tokenization, and the new payment
systems. And the US should not let that
infrastructure be built elsewhere. This
is the same thing they have said about
AI. So if you are doubting it now at a
time when Bitcoin and the crypto market
has no positive sentiment and as I go
through very reminiscent of where we
were in AI a year and three months ago
when I was buying Micron below 100 and
people were telling me there was nothing
happening. I wrote a paper on inference
in May. Crickets
best in Stockman appears to treat
dollar-based stable coins as a way to
extend the dollar. Do not fight digital
dollars. Regulate them.
For Bitcoin, the implication is
different but complimentary, which I'll
get through.
As an investor, is it important to do
your homework on digital assets, stable
coins, and how they fit in the future. I
just literally went through and asked uh
an LLM on this.
What happens to the financial system
when money, collateral, payment,
settlement, and eventually AI, agent,
commerce all become programmable? That's
really where we are at this point. And
the reason that I want you guys to do
that homework is that I also want you to
go back after you've read Muhammad Alan,
after you've read Scott Besson, and then
go back to Mark Andre and what he posted
on January 21st, 2014 titled Why Bitcoin
Matters. Eventually, mainstream
products, companies, and industries
emerged to commercialize it. Its effects
become profound. And later, many people
wonder why its powerful promise wasn't
more obvious from the start. What
technology am I talking about? Personal
computers in 1975, the internet in 1993,
and I believe Bitcoin in 2014.
People didn't accept the internet as a
big thing, meaning accept that it was
real, until effectively the iPhone came
out. That was when everything became
real. We were in a bare market in tech
in the from the dotcom bubble. So,
Bitcoin, we're now 12 years ahead. This
was 14 years ahead. He's talking about
personal computers. You guys can go back
and look at when they were accepted.
To finish up further, there is no
shortage of regulatory topics and issues
that will have to be addressed as part
of Bitcoin since almost no country's
regulatory framework for banking and
payments accepted a technology like
Bitcoin. Well, we've made it through
this, guys. the US government, the
leader of the free world, not only won
an election on it, is putting regulatory
uh uh framework in,
but they're doing it at the same time as
AI. But I hope I've given you a sense of
the enormous promise of Bitcoin. Bitcoin
offers a sweeping vista of opportunity
to imagine how the financial system can
and should be worked. This is the most
important thing. reimagine how the
financial system can and should work in
the internet era and a catalyst to
reshape that system in ways that are
more powerful for individuals and
businesses alike.
Andre told investors why Bitcoin
mattered before the state understood it.
Vesson is now telling policy makers why
it matters. Agentic AI commerce is the
accelerant. Once AI agents become
transacting, consuming compute, managing
subscriptions, settling invoices, moving
it, the payment system becomes the
operating layer of the agent economy. In
2014, Andre saw the internet's need for
the native value transfer. In 2026,
Betton recognized it. Guys, this is a
no-brainer. It's a no-brainer to go
spend the time on it. Jeremy Grantham is
doing rants about Bitcoin, saying it is
worthless. He has Again, I I don't know
how to say this anymore. People do not
pay attention. They were saying the same
thing about AI. It was hallucinating. I
was on trips last year hearing about how
the hallucinations would always
presented. It was garbage. It would
never be adopted. it would never go
through. So I wrote this paper in May
15, 2025. The inference inflection where
real-time assets meet real world
opportunity. We're just getting started
with the upcoming rise of AI agents.
This is in May of 2015. AI native phones
and PCs and embodied AI like
self-driving platforms and humanoid
robots. Inference demand is poised to go
parabolic. The implications for
semiconductors, memory, networking,
power, and edge computer are massive. If
Q1 earnings, this is Q1 of last year,
told us anything, it's that scalable
inference infrastructure has officially
arrived. Crickets last year when I wrote
this piece, and I'm sure crypto right
now gets crickets. Now, if you guys want
to go read stuff from March of this
year, why cons when consumers become
agents, the open claw gateway? Well,
that proved to be right for the agentic
side. Tokenization, when ownerships
become programmable. You guys can go
look at this on your own. This is all
what's coming, guys. have written about
it now for the last year and a half on
is all on Substack
Stripe sessions and the coming agentic
commerce economy. The reason this is on
Substack so everyone traditional finance
is realizing is because most people
don't pay attention to crypto. And so
what I do on the subscriber wall, what I
do in the stuff that I do with 22V
clients, I don't talk about crypto at
all. For you, those of you on the crypto
side, I know you buy into this. I know
you get it. But all of these things,
this is from June 30th. Stripe sessions
and the coming agentic commerce. They're
showing you what's happening. It's
already going on from public. Well,
these guys are not public, but it's
there. This is why I've shown this. This
will be part of the video. This will be
the main framework around it. The blue
line here is the 40 name index.
40 names to create the crypto index that
I've created. These are broken up into
eight verticals which are effectively
sectors. If you go through them, there
are 34 that are tokens. representing
the private world or the crypto world
and there are six that are now public
companies things like circle
equal weight it is an overlay with
bitcoin so at the end of the day I will
continue to say bitcoin is the S&P 500
of the future of tokenization you can
believe it you can doubt it you can do
whatever but for all of you that are
doubting it particularly the raas and
fas that have your money inside public
companies and inside real estate and
inside all of these different things the
capital structure of the world is
changing Scott Bessant has told you that
it is changing and it will be
represented by this stuff. This is where
you're going to find the growth assets.
This is where you're going to find the
things that are going higher. This is
what I will be putting together for the
next video thing on YouTube, which will
effectively be like this, but it'll be
starting from the place not of the AI
side. It'll be where AI meets stable
coins tokenization and the new financial
guard rails. That is what I'll be going
through. That is what I'll be showing
you. Now to finish up, Bitcoin still a
bare market. Technically, I showed you
guys last week. I it it traded well
again this week. We made the low here. I
had divergence signals. We're still
there. The 50-day is the next line in
the sand as far as I'm concerned. We get
above there and then we'll worry about
the 200 day. Uh that's what I'm looking
at. Doge, which I told you, and for
those who don't care about Doge, Doge is
retail energy. That's what I care about.
I want to see it get above the 200 day
as well. We're way below. We didn't even
get above the 20-day yet. We did on
Bitcoin. So, there's no energy yet.
Retail is not comfortable in this.
Michael Sailor did something that anyone
said if he ever did, Bitcoin would be
down big. He sold a chunk of Bitcoin.
About 3,500 coins.
This is when the announcement came out.
This is what happened to Bitcoin.
Oh, guess what? Closed higher than it
was when that announcement came out. So,
we had positive response to bad news
just like I highlighted last week. So,
I'm going to finish up the last three
slides here. I wrote a paper on the
academic Fed versus the inflation target
of the future. If you guys didn't get a
chance to do it, I highly recommend it.
I think it is critical as we come into
what I think is the only month that the
Fed
would really raise rates. That's my
belief is that if they're going to raise
rates and he wants to get the Fed
credibility, why not do it uh in July?
uh it's close to 50% but to do it I do
think there'll be some sort of wink wink
nod nod even though he said he's not
going to do any forward guidance I do
believe that something would probably
come out because I don't think as his
first thing he wants to disappoint the
market especially with his uh with
Donald Trump who just brought him in. I
think there's a lot of things in here
for people to read about in terms of the
impact that AI is going to have on the
Fed. And all I'm using is Kevin Worsh's
words from his confirmation hearing and
from an interview he did with the ECB
forum last week. I also put this out on
Substack. If you guys aren't getting my
Substack, go subscribe to it for the
Trady [clears throat] people. I think
now more than ever reading what I'm
writing about on crypto. I connected
Bitcoin to that art of unlearning the
Fed and why it matters. And the main
reason why it matters is this chart
here. So this is the rate cuts, the
white line here. So, we were expected to
have 150 uhund
uh
yeah, we were supposed to have the rate
cuts in here and now we've got rate
hikes down here.
So, we went from a position of rate
cuts, we did a cut here, we did a cut
here, and then the rest of this is
turning it from future cuts by December
of this year to hikes. This is Bitcoin
overlaid with it. So as they got more
hawkish as we started to see an ending
to the cut cycle and fears this
happened. Now we also the green line
here was growth verse value which was
really the software side. This has
broken and I think the Fed side is going
to break. One or two things are going to
happen. I don't think if the Fed does
hike I think it's one and done and I
think it's 25. I think you'll probably
see long-term rates come down on the
back of it with the Fred credibility. If
they don't do it, which I don't think
they will, uh I I'm going to stick with
the fact that they're not going to do
anything and I'm going to stick with my
paper. Uh and I think at that point you
can have some tailwinds for Bitcoin.
And that's it for this week, guys. Um
again, thanks to everyone. Uh I'll be up
in Maine the rest of the summer and I'll
keep you up to date. See you next week.